RACHAEL ENFIELD

3D PRINT & RESEARCH ASSISTANT

ABOUT

I am an energetic sophomore working as both a 3D print assistant and a lab assistant. My goal is to work with 3D food printers to find more efficient ways to distribute food product to lower transportation costs and reduce food waste. I hope to achieve these goals through my research, programming skills and experiences.

CONTACT

(617) 645 8914 rachaelenfield@msn.com renfield@umass.edu

EXPERIENCE

3D PRINT ASSISTANT | DIGITAL MEDIA LAB | SEPT 2016 - PRESENT

- Engage with public regarding 3D printing and our service
- Responsibilities include providing technical assistance on designing and processing CAD models for 3D printing or 3D print related issues
- Perform maintenance of printer and scanner hardware and software regularly

RESEARCH ASSISTANT | CORRADINI LAB | MAY 2016 - PRESENT

- Working under Professor Maria Corradini in the food science department
- Worked with a visiting professor and grad students on research projects
- Learned procedures and techniques for lab research and data analysis

IT INTERN | LASELL COLLEGE | MAY 2016 - JUNE 2016

- Interned in IT department, setting up computers and labs
- Set up maker space with two 3D printers and a 3D scanner and created documentation for setting up and troubleshooting 3D printers
- Scrum Master of the intern group

INTERESTS

CNS STUDENT LEADERSHIP COMMITTEE

- Collaborating with the Associate Deans of the College of Natural Science to better the lives of students in the school
- Student Ambassador to encourage perspective students to apply and attend

FOOD SCIENCE PRODUCT DEVELOPMENT TEAM

• Competed in product development contests to create new food products for companies

SKILLS

Proficient in both Mac and PC operating systems as well as office products for both. Educated in 3D printer set-up and handling (Makergear and Makerbot). Knowledgeable in programming languages Java and Python. Experienced in HTML and CSS web design. Familiar with PHP and SQL.

EDUCATION

UNIVERSITY OF MASSACHUSETTS, 2020

Bachelor of Science, Pursing Major in Food Science with Minor in Computer Science